Michael Scott Bond

5850 Cameron Run Terrace #203, Alexandria, VA 22303 | michael.s.bond@gmail.com | (740) 972-9157

Executive Summary

- Proficient Fluent in Mandarin
- Current Graduate Student at George Washington University, focusing on Graduate Course Work Focused on Defense Analysis and Research
- 2 Year Experience in Quantitative

Analysis and Modeling

5+ Years in China Research, Translation, and Analysis

making it look like something that you've completed. Otherwise, they'll be confused

Formatted: Centered

why you have education first.

Comment [k3]: Put this closer to the top/bigger font so they know you're almost

Comment [k1]: Recommend using "proficient." Worry you might get called out

Comment [k2]: Changed emphasis to show you're currently in grad school, rather than

Formatted: Font: 12 pt

Formatted: Font: 12 pt

Formatted: Font: 10 pt

Formatted: List Paragraph, Bulleted + Level: 1 + Aligned at: 0.25" + Indent at:

0.5"

Comment [k4]: Or use 2009-2011 or whatever. It saves space, makes it look less repetitive. Did you do two separate Bacherlors Degrees? Or is this a dual major?

Formatted: Font: Not Bold

Formatted: Font: 10 pt

Formatted: List Paragraph, Bulleted + Level: 1 + Aligned at: 0.25" + Indent at:

Formatted: Centered

Comment [k5]: Use past tense. You did it, you completed these task.

Comment [k6]: Keep an eye on this-some words capitalized while others are not. Only capitalize for set phrases: Program Management vs. I managed a program.

Comment [k7]: You traveled right? Were you a rep? Did you represent your company in negotiations, conferences, do any problem solving? Show what you learned here.

Formatted: Font: 10 pt

Formatted: Space After: 10 pt, Line spacing: Multiple 1.15 li

Comment [k8]: What did you learn by doing this? What skills did you need to accomplish it? This is not an easy task- it takes creativity, autonomy, a strong sense of ownership [... [1]

Comment [k9]: For how many people? Visiting scholars or VIPs?

Education

The George Washington University______

Expected Graduation: May 2018

Graduation: June 2011

Elliot School of International Affair, Washington DC

M.A Candidate Security Policy Studies

- Expected Graduation: May 2018

____Concentrations: Defense Analysis, Statistics

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH_

Graduated 2011

<u>Dual Major</u> B.A. Mandarin Chinese, <u>B.A in and International Studies</u> (GPA 3.48) Graduation: June 2011

-Three semesters study abroad In Qinqdao, PRC

- B.A. International Studies (GPA 3.48)
- _Concentration on Chinese Military Affairs

Professional Experience

Crest Financial, Virginia, North Carolina

Outside Sales Representative,

October 2015-Present

- Manageding \$3 million in sales for the region of southern Maryland, Virginia, and North Carolina
- Collection, Analysis, and reporting of regional sales data
- **Business to Business Sales**
- -Conflict Resolution OTHER SKILLS?

Voice of America, Washington DC

Researcher, Mandarin Service

July 2012-December 2015

- Research for news reports, defense focus
- Mandarin Chinese to English translation and transcription
- Television and Radio Program Hosting,
- Social Media Account Management
- Use of Adobe and Google Analytics for collection and interpretation of web traffic data-

The American Mandarin Society, Washington, DC

Chinese Military Policy Analyst

April 2013-April 2014

- Open Source research of the People's Liberation Army strategic policy trends, advances in military equipment and training,
- Curated and created content social media page
- Organizational Event Planning for small and medium groups with visiting scholars
- University outreach and new member recruitment

Professional Skills

Foreign Language: Mandarin Chinese (<u>Proficient Fluent</u> Speaking and Reading, Intermediate Writing) **Computers:** Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Project, Adobe Analytics, SPSS, Linear/Non-Linear Modeling, Security+ Certified

International Experience: Ohio State-Oceans University Summer Exchange Program in China (2009, 2010, 2011), Independent Student Travel in China, Mexico, and U.K.

What did you learn by doing this? What skills did you need to accomplish it? This is not an easy task- it takes creativity, autonomy, a strong sense of ownership of the final project, team work, cross-cultural competencies, etc...